Sierra Club, Atlantic Chapter; Records apap130
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1967-1998; 4; 13.17 cubic ft.
  - Pesticides, Health Research Science Board (NYS), 1996 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Pesticides, Legislation, Federal, 1987-1988 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Pesticides, Legislation, State, 1993; 1995 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Pesticides, Long Island, 1993-1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Pesticides, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, 1996-1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Pesticides, Ordinances, 1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Pesticides, Pataki Policy Decisions, 1995 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Pesticides, Profile 2SC, Undated (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Pesticides, Pest Management, 1993; 1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Pesticides, The Pesticide Project, 1996-1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Pesticides, Pesticide Right-to-Know and Reduction Act, 1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Pesticides, Registration, 1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Pesticides, Reporting System for Pesticide Use, 1995-1996 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Pesticides, Reports by Private Organizations, 1992; 1996 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Pesticides, Schools, 1993-1996 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Pesticides, United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1995-1997 (Box 8 (4-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Pesticides, Use Reduction, 1994 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Press Coverage, National Issues, 1988-1990 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Press Coverage, State Issues, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3-4)
  - Press Coverage, State Issues, 1991; Undated (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Public Health, Capital District Tobacco-Free Coalition, 1997? (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Public Health, Breast Cancer, 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Public Health, Children's Health Environmental Coalition, 1997 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Public Health, Comparative Risk Project, 1997; 8 folders (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9-16)
  - Public Health, Electromagnetic Fields (EMFs), 1991-1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Public Health, Kids Against Pollution, 1996-1997 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Public Health, Life Preservers, 1996 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Public Health, National Health Care, 1991 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Public Health, Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Public Health, Tobacco Products, 1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Batteries, 1991 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Beverage, Containers and Deposits, 1973-1984; 2 folders (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24-25)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Beverage, Containers and Deposits, 1993-1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Beverage Containers and Deposits, 1994; 4 folders (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27-30)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Burn Barrels, 1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Composting, 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Economic Benefits, 1992 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Ethanol, 1996 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Flow Control of Municipal Solid Waste, 1994-1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, General, 1994 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Guide to Recycling by Sen. Oppenheimer, ca. 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Incineration, 1991-1995; 2 folders (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38-39)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Institute for Local Self-Reliance, 1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Juice Boxes, 1991 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Landfills, 1990-1992 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Municipal Efforts, 1990-1992 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New Facility Permit Applications, 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York City Litter, 1972 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York City Solid Waste Management Plan, 1992 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York State Assembly Reports on Garbage Disposal, 1994-1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York State Office of Recycling Market Development, 1991; 1993 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York State Regulations, 1988; 1993; 1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, New York State State Solid Waste Management Plan, 1990-1995 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Newsletters, 1995-1996 (Box 9 (4-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Paper, 1997 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Plastics and Packaging, 1982; 1991-1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Presidential Executive Order, 1993 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Sanctions for Violations, 1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Sierra Club Priorities, 1992 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Soil Remediation, 1997 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Wisconsin Recycling Fee, 1991 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Recycling and Solid Waste, Tires, 1992; 1996 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Agriculture and "Biosolids", 1982-1990 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Agriculture and "Biosolids", 1992 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Agriculture and "Biosolids", 1994-1997; 4 folders (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11-14)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Agriculture and "Biosolids", Undated (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Contaminants, 1989-1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Fish Creek Discharge, 1990 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Health Effects, 1992-1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Legislation, 1993; 1997 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Methanol, 1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Sewage and Sludge, National Sludge Alliance, 1996-1997 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Sewage and Sludge, National Sludge Roundtable, 1996 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Sewage and Sludge, New Jersey, 1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Sewage and Sludge, New York City, 1996 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Sewage and Sludge, New York State Roundtable, 1994-1996; 3 folders (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25-27)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Ocean Arks International, ca. 1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Onondaga County, 1995 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Pollution Prevention, 1994 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Research, 1981; 1992 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Sewage and Sludge, Risk Assessment, Undated (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Sewage and Sludge, United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1992 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - State Bonds, ACTION Bond Act, 1983 (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - State Bonds, Clean Water/Clean Air Bond Act, 1996-1999; 6 folders (Box 10 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35-40)
  - State Bonds, Environmental Quality Bond Act, 1986 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - State Bonds, Environmental Quality Bond Act, 1990 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - State Bonds, Infrastructure Bond Act, 1983 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - State Bonds, New New York Bond Act, 1992 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - State Bonds, Reform, 1997 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Storm King Mountain, Brief of Consolidated Edison, 1967 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Storm King Mountain, Brief of Sierra Club and Atlantic Chapter, 1967 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Storm King Mountain, Reply Brief by Scenic Hudson, 1967; 2 folders (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8-9)
  - Storm King Mountain, Reply Brief of Sierra Club and Atlantic Chapter, 1967; 2 folders (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10-11)
  - Storm King Mountain, Federal Power Commission Staff Brief, 1967 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Storm King Mountain, Federal Power Commission Staff Reply Brief, 1967 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Storm King Mountain, Examiner's Initial Decision, 1968 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Takings (Eminent Domain), 1987-1997; 3 folders (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15-17)
  - Transportation, Adirondack Park, 1994-1996 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Transportation, Alternative Fuels, 1993 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Transportation, Amendments, Undated (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Transportation, Automobile Industry, 1992; 2 folders (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21-22)
  - Transportation, Automobile Mileage, 1991 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Transportation, Biofuels, 1995 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Transportation, Electric Cars, 1997 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Transportation, Empire State Passengers Association, 1995 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Transportation, Fuel Cells, 1991; 1997 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Transportation, Gasoline Tax, 1990 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Transportation, High Speed Rail and Maglevs, 1993 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Transportation, Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act (ISTEA), 1991-1992; 1997 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Transportation, Kingston Arterial, 1976 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Transportation, Local Transit, 1990; 1992 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Transportation, Low Emission Vehicles, 1991 (Box 11 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Transportation, Low Emission Vehicles, 1992; 1995? (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Transportation, New York Legislation and Policy, 1995; 1997 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Transportation, Ohio Transportation Policy, 1996 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Transportation, Reformulated Gasoline, 1995 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Transportation, Truck Length, 1990 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Transportation, Westway, 1984 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Transportation, Westway, 1995-1997 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Water Quality and Use, Acid Rain, 1983-1987; 3 folders (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8-10)
  - Water Quality and Use, Antidegradation Efforts, 1990 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Water Quality and Use, Bridges, Dams and Ports, 1982-1983; 1994 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Water Quality and Use, Canal System, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13-14)
  - Water Quality and Use, Clean Water Act, 1983-1984 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Water Quality and Use, Clean Water Act, 1994; Undated (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Water Quality and Use, Coastal Management, 1993-1994 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Water Quality and Use, Coastal Nonpoint Pollution, 1993 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Water Quality and Use, Dredging, 1992-1997 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Water Quality and Use, Drinking Water, 1981-1983; 1988 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Water Quality and Use, Drinking Water, 1992-1997 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Water Quality and Use, Filtration/Cryptosporidiosis, 1995-1997 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Water Quality and Use, Fisherman's Right to Know Act, 1993 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Water Quality and Use, Groundwater, 1984; 1990 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Water Quality and Use, Hydroelectric Plants, 1994 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Water Quality and Use, Industrial Pretreatment, 1984-1989 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Water Quality and Use, Lake Champlain, 1996 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Water Quality and Use, Leasing of Underwater Lands, 1988 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Water Quality and Use, National Water Quality Inventory (US EPA), 1996 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Water Quality and Use, New York Harbor, 1995 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Water Quality and Use, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation Division of Water, 1990 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Water Quality and Use, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation Division of Water, ca. 1995 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Water Quality and Use, New York State Revolving Fund for Water Pollution Control, 1990-1991 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Water Quality and Use, Nonpoint Source Pollution, 1994-1995 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Water Quality and Use, Pelham Bay, 1991 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Water Quality and Use, Pollution, 1995-1998 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Water Quality and Use, Pond Liming, 1984 (Box 12 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Water Quality and Use, Rivers and Streams, 1982-1989 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Water Quality and Use, Rivers and Streams, 1990-1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Water Quality and Use, Soil and Water Conservation, 1994 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Water Quality and Use, State Pollution Discharge Elimination System (SPDES), 1994 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Water Quality and Use, Suffolk County, 1993? (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Water Quality and Use, Surface Waters, 1984-1985 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Water Quality and Use, Takings and Clean Water, 1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Water Quality and Use, Toxic Fish, 1993-1997 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Water Quality and Use, Wastewater, 1982-1984 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Water Quality and Use, Water Resources Management, 1990; 1992 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Water Quality and Use, Watersheds - Croton, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11-12)
  - Water Quality and Use, Watersheds - New York City, 1994-1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Water Quality and Use, Wetlands, 1984; 1993-1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Albany Pine Bush Preserve, 1991-1992 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, 1992; 1995 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Artificial Reefs, 1995-1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Bald Eagles, 1989 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Balloons, Prohibition of Release of, 1993 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Bears, 1993 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Beavers, 1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Biodiversity, 1993 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Bison, 1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Critical Ecoregions Program, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24-25)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Earth Summit, 1992 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Endangered Species Act, 1991; 1993; 1997 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Essential Habitats Protection, 1991 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Great Lakes, 1983-1984 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Great Lakes Ecoregion Taskforce, 1993-1995 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Great Northern Forest/Northern Forest Alliance, 1993-1995 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Gypsy Moths, 1982-1983 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Hudson River National Estuarine Sanctuary, 1982; 1992; 1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Long Island Pine Barrens, 1992-1993 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Moose, 1992 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, National Organization's Wildlife Policy, 1991 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, New York State Department of Environmental Conservation News Releases, 1992 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Prescribed Burning, 1991 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Rogers Environmental Education Center, 1989 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Wildlife Habitat Protection, Legal Aspects of, 1982 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Wildlife and Habitat, Wolves, 1996 (Box 13 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Adirondack Park, Commission on the Adirondacks in the Twenty-First Century, ca. 1991 (Box 14 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Communications and Media, 1996 (Box 14 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
- James Bay Hydroelectric Project, 1989-1994; 5; 3.77 cubic ft.
  This series documents the Atlantic Chapter's efforts to stop the proposed hydroelectric project near James Bay in northern Quebec in the early 1990s. Hydro-Quebec, the province's public electrical utility, intended to build a series of hydroelectric stations on the Great Whale River (Fr. Grande Baleine), and sell the electricity produced in the United States, particularly to New York and Vermont. This was the second phase of a larger project dating back to 1971. The project involved flooding a large area of northern Quebec, which opponents claimed would have drowned the breeding grounds of several wildlife species, released deposits of mercury into the environment, and disrupted the subsistence habits of the Cree Indians of Quebec. New York State signed two contracts with Hydro-Quebec for James Bay electricity, one for 800 megawatts (MW) and the other for 1000MW in 1989. Efforts by the Sierra Club and other organizations to cancel the contracts began almost immediately, and the project gained wide media attention by 1991-1992, due in part to publicity tours by the Quebec Cree and Inuit in the United States. The contracts were cancelled in 1992 and 1994. Items found in the series include papers by various American and Canadian environmental organizations, materials relating to the two contracts, items by and about the Cree Indians of Quebec, Hydro-Quebec documents (including the complete twenty-seven volume Grande Baleine Complex feasibility study, and a study of the related Sainte Marguerite-3 hydroelectric project), economic and ecological studies, and relevant New York State documents.
  - Activist Contact Lists, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 1)
  - Advertisement in the New York Times, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 2)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Capital District Greens, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 3)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Environmental Planning Lobby, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 4)
  - American Environmental Organizations, James Bay and Northern Wilderness Task Force, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 5)
  - American Environmental Organizations, James Bay Defense Coalition, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 6)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Liberal Party of New York State, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 7)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Massachusetts Save James Bay, Inc., 1993-1994 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 8)
  - American Environmental Organizations, National Audubon Society, 1989-1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 9)
  - American Environmental Organizations, National Resources Defense Council, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 10)
  - American Environmental Organizations, New York City Energy Independence Task Force, 1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 11)
  - American Environmental Organizations, New York James Bay Network, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 12)
  - American Environmental Organizations, New York Public Interest Research Group (NYPIRG), 1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 13)
  - American Environmental Organizations, New York State Conservation Council, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 14)
  - American Environmental Organizations, New York State Trapper's Association, Undated (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 15)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Northeast Regional James Bay Action Conference, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 16)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Prudent Residents Opposed to Electric Cable Transmission (PROTECT), 1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 17)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Sierra Student Coalition, 1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 18)
  - American Environmental Organizations, Solidarity Foundation, 1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 19)
  - American Express, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 20)
  - American Indian Community House, Inc., 1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 21)
  - Aquatic Environments, 1990-1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 22)
  - Audley, John, Undated (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 23)
  - Brown, Ruben S./E3 Co., 1991-1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 24)
  - "Canadian Electricity Imports: An Assessment of the National Security, Economic, and Environmental Implications", 1998 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 25)
  - Canadian Environmental Organizations, Arctic Institute of North America, 1990 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 26)
  - Canadian Environmental Organizations, Canadian Arctic Resources Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 27)
  - Canadian Environmental Organizations, Canadian Ecology Advocates, 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 28)
  - Canadian Environmental Organizations, Hudson Bay Programme, 1994 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 29)
  - Canadian Water Watch, 1990 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 30)
  - Clich, David, 1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 31)
  - Conferences, 1994 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 32)
  - Contracts, 800 Megawatt Contract, 1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 33)
  - Contracts, 1000 Megawatt Contract, 1989; 1991 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 34)
  - Corporations and the Media, Undated (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 36)
  - Cost of James Bay Electricity, ca. 1992 (Box 1 (5-James Bay Hydroelectric Pr), Folder 37)